R. Paul Fornia

(303) 859-9753 paulfornia@gmail.com www.paulfornia.com

Paul is an experienced data scientist, programmer, consultant, and team leader. He specializes in bringing powerful machine learning models into real situations quickly and practically, with a focus on value and impact. He has served clients from several industries, including government, non-profit, and healthcare.

In addition to a strong foundation in math and statistics, Paul has 8 years of programming experience in a wide variety of languages, including C++, Java, SAS, SQL, and especially Python and R. He is also comfortable with industry-standard tools used in the data science pipeline such as Linux, Git, AWS and Agile processes. He has several years of experience leading small teams and mentoring junior data scientists.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DataRobot - Customer Facing Data Scientist (CFDS), Remote & Traveling

2019 - 2020

Al for Good program, providing pro bono services to social impact organizations

- Primary CFDS for five high-value clients
- · Scope and develop machine learning use cases for maximum ROI and impact
- · Execute machine learning projects from framing to modeling to deployment
- Provide support and data science consulting on the DataRobot software platform
- Support sales team by demoing DataRobot to executives and at trade shows
- Help guide formation and strategy for the AI for Good program
- Represent the program internally and externally in media interviews

Deloitte - Senior Consultant and Data Scientist, Washington, DC

2014 - 2019

Analytics | Federal Sector

- Developed Machine Learning, Optimization, Recommenders, and UI solutions
- Led team of four full-time consultants and data scientists
- Managed complex software development life-cycle
- Developed and led internal and external trainings in Data Science

Federal Reserve Board of Governors - Senior Research Assistant, Washington, DC

2012 - 2014

Financial Studies | Research & Statistics

- Contributed analysis to support original policy and academic research
- Managed data sets and models, and data visualizations
- Trained junior research assistants on data analysis and visualization tools

EDUCATION

Johns Hopkins University (IN PROGRESS) Anticipated Summer 2020 MS – Computer Science **University of Colorado Boulder** 2012 BA—Economics—Magna cum Laude BS—Applied Mathematics—Computational Economics Emphasis **NON-DEGREE EDUCATION and CERTIFICATIONS Certified Cloud Practitioner** 2018 **Amazon Web Services University of Washington** 2017 Specialization in Machine Learning - Coursera **Johns Hopkins University** 2015 Specialization in Data Science - Coursera The George Washington University 2014 Graduate Certificate in Financial Math **PUBLICATIONS**

S Cheong, R Fornia, G Lee, et al., 2012, *The Japanese Economy in Crisis: A Time Series Segmentation Study*. Economics E-Journal: Vol 6 2012-5, 1-81